A Guide to the Carrie T. Sibold Family Papers, 1912-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Carrie T. Sibold Family Papers, 1912-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1990-043
Carrie T. Sibold's VPI diploma has been digitized and is available online.
14.8 Cubic Feet; 12 boxes and 1 folder
The collection consists of scrapbooks, journals, V.P.I. reunion materials, photograph albums, family diplomas, and the diary of Nannie V. Sibold. As a whole, the collection dates from 1912 to 1990. However, Carrie T. Sibold's scrapbook journals, which run from 1974 to 1990, constitute the the bulk of the collection material.
Sibold, Nannie V. (Nannie Virginia), 1897-1957
Sibold, Carrie T. (Carrie Taylor), 1904-1990
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Carrie T. Sibold Family Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1990 and in October 2012.
Alternate Form Available
Carrie T. Sibold's VPI diploma has been digitized and is available online.
Biographical Note
Carrie T. Sibold (1904-1990) was one of the first women graduates at Virginia Tech, earning a B.S. in Biology in 1925. She formed part of the first class of women who enrolled as freshmen in 1921. Sibold worked for the Virginia Tech Alumni Office until her retirement in 1966. Afterward, she remained an active member of V.P.I.'s "Old Guard" and assisted in the arrangement of class reunions. Sibold was also known locally for her extensive doll collection.
Scope and Content
The Carrie T. Sibold Papers consists of scrapbooks, journals, V.P.I. reunion materials, photograph albums, family diplomas, and the diary of Nannie V. Sibold. As a whole, the collection dates from 1912 to 1990. However, Carrie. T. Sibold's scrapbook journals, which run from 1974 to 1990, constitute the the bulk of the collection material.
The journals and other scrapbooks contain a record of Carrie Sibold's daily activities, as well as newspaper clippings. Many of these clippings concern local events and history, local church activities, Blacksburg high school and college sports teams, television shows Carrie Sibold watched or intended to watch, soap opera summaries, and celebrity news. These journals document Carrie Sibold's life after her retirement.
Dating from 1912 to 1926, the diplomas include grammar school and high school diplomas for members of Carrie Sibold's family, as well as her bachelor's degree from VPI. The papers series contains various documents and papers related to the VPI alumni organization and reunion arrangements, as well as the diary of Nannie V. Sibold, which she kept from 1935 to 1939. The collection also includes eight photograph albums, most of which do not provide identification for the individuals pictured.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into four series:
Series I: Notebooks - arranged by primary type of content
Subseries A: Journals/Organizers - Sibold's personal journals and planners arranged chronologically
Subseries B: Clippings - notebooks of newspaper clippings on TV, movies, local and national news, and science/nature - arranged chronologically
Subseries C: Scrapbooks - notebooks used as scrapbooks, featuring newspaper clippings, church materials, and items of interest collected by Sibold - arranged chronologically
Series II: Family Diplomas - arranged chronologically
Series III: Papers - arranged by material type
Series IV: Photograph Albums - arranged by material type
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Materials
Mattie Lamb Tucker Papers, Ms1984-176.
Blacksburg Oral History Project Records, Ms1985-005. Includes an oral history interview with Carrie Sibold.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); University Archives; University History; Women -- History
Organizations:
Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Persons:
Sibold, Carrie T. (Carrie Taylor), 1904-1990; Sibold, Nannie V. (Nannie Virginia), 1897-1957; Sibold, Chloe M., 1899-1976; Sibold, Thomas W. (Thomas William), 1909-1930
Contents List
Carrie T. Sibold's VPI diploma has been digitized and is available online.
- Series I: Notebooks, 1954-1990
  - Subseries A: Journals/Organizers
    - Scrapbook journal, 1974-01-01-1974-06-30 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1974-07-01-1974-08-11 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1974-08-12-1974-12-22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1974-12-23-1975-03-09 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1975-03-10-1975-06-14 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1975-06-15-1975-08-31 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1975-09-01-1975-10-27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1975-10-28-1976-01-31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1976-02-01-1976-04-16 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1976-04-17-1976-07-31 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1976-08-01-1976-11-23 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1976-11-24-1977-01-31 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1977-02-01-1977-04-15 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1977-04-16-1977-05-31 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1977-06-01-1977-08-05 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1977-08-06-1977-09-23 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1977-09-24-1977-10-19 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1977-10-20-1977-11-23 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1977-11-24-1977-12-31 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1978-01-01-1978-02-18 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1978-02-19-1978-03-30 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1978-04-01-1978-05-12 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1978-05-13-1978-06-30 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1978-07-01-1978-08-14 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1978-08-15-1978-09-28 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1978-09-29-1978-10-31 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1978-11-01-1978-11-30 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1978-12-01-1978-12-31 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-01-01-1979-01-31 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-02-01-1979-02-28 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-03-01-1979-04-04 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-04-05-1979-04-30 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-05-01-1979-06-10 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-06-11-1979-07-29 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-07-31-1979-09-11 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-09-12-1979-10-11 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-10-12-1979-11-15 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-11-16-1979-12-20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1979-12-21-1980-01-21 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1980-01-22-1980-02-23 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1980-02-24-1980-04-05 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1980-04-06-1980-05-17 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1980-05-18-1980-06-26 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1980-06-27-1980-08-08 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1980-08-09-1980-09-25 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1980-09-26-1980-10-31 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1980-11-01-1980-11-30 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1980-12-01-1981-01-14 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1981-01-15-1981-02-25 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1981-02-26-1981-04-07 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1981-04-08-1981-05-31 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1981-06-01-1981-07-31 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1981-08-01-1981-09-12 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1981-09-13-1981-10-23 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1981-10-24-1981-11-30 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1981-12-01-1982-01-10 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1982-01-11-1982-02-04 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1982-02-05-1982-02-28 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1982-03-01-1982-04-24 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1982-04-25-1982-06-05 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1982-06-06-1982-07-24 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1982-07-25-1982-09-24 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1982-09-25-1982-11-30 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1982-12-01-1983-01-08 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1983-01-09-1983-02-28 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1983-03-01-1983-03-31 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1983-04-01-1983-05-07 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1983-05-08-1983-06-25 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1983-06-26-1983-08-03 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1983-08-04-1983-09-17 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1983-09-18-1983-10-31 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1983-11-01-1983-12-10 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1983-12-11-1984-01-14 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1984-01-15-1984-02-13 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1984-02-14-1984-04-21 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1984-04-22-1984-05-18 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1984-05-19-1984-07-28 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1984-07-24-1984-09-29 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1984-09-30-1984-11-17 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1984-11-18-1985-01-12 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1985-01-13-1985-02-05 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1985-02-06-1985-03-13 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1985-03-14-1985-04-03 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1985-04-04-1985-05-25 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1985-05-26-1985-07-06 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1985-07-07-1985-08-31 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1985-09-01-1985-10-12 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1985-10-13-1985-11-16 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1985-11-17-1985-12-25 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1985-12-26-1986-01-18 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1986-01-19-1986-03-13 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1986-03-14-1986-04-28 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1986-04-29-1986-06-02 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1986-06-03-1986-07-12 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1986-07-13-1986-08-25 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1986-08-26-1986-09-21 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1986-09-22-1986-10-14 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1986-10-15-1986-11-07 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1986-11-08-1986-12-04 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1987-09-11-1987-10-15 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1987-10-19-1987-11-14 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1987-11-15-1987-12-15 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1987-12-16-1988-01-23 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1988-01-24-1988-03-08 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1988-03-09-1988-05-21 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1988-05-22-1988-08-07 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1988-08-08-1988-09-08 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1988-09-09-1988-10-31 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1988-11-01-1989-01-07 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1989-01-08-1989-03-25 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook journal, 1989-11-12-1990-01-07 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Monthly Planner, 1986-01-1988-12 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Monthly Planner, 1989-01-1990-11 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Subseries B: Clippings
    - News clippings, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Pictures, movies, and TV, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Pictures and articles, 1976-01-1976-02 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Pictures, articles, etc., 1950, 1976-01-1976-03 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Pictures, etc., 1976-04-1976-05 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Pictures, 1976-06-1976-07 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Pictures, 1976-09-1976-11 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Pictures, movies, and radio, 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Pictures, 1976-12-1977-01 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - News clippings, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - News clippings, 1977-02-1977-09 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Pictures, movies, and TV, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Movies and TV, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Movies and TV, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Pictures, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Nature and animals, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - News clippings, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Nature and animals, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - TV and movies, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - News clippings, 1978-1985 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - News clippings, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Nature and animals, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Subseries C: Notebooks/Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook - old pictures and local news, 1954-1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Programs, rhymes, and talks, 1963-1976 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Notebook, 1963, 1970, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Notebook, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Notebook, 1969, 1971, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Notebook - pennies, 1970-1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Speeches and rhymes, 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Scrapbook - church, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Notebook - Elizabeth Cochrane AKA Nelly Bly, 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Notebook - Books I, ca. 1974 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Notebook - Books II, ca. 1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Notebook - Books III, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Notebook - Books IV, 1978-1982 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Notebook - Books IV, associated papers, 1974-1981 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Harding Avenue Elementary School, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Poems, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Series II: Family Diplomas, 1912-1926
  - Nannie Sibold, Certificate of Promotion to the High School, 1912 (Folder 1)
  - Chloe Sibold, Certificate of Promotion to the High School, 1913 (Folder 1)
  - Nannie Virginia Sibold, High School Diploma, 1916 (Folder 1)
  - Carrie Sibold, Certificate of Promotion to the High School, 1917 (Folder 1)
  - Chloe Sibold, High School Diploma, 1917 (Folder 1)
  - Carrie Taylor Sibold, High School Diploma, 1921 (Folder 1)
  - Carrie Taylor Sibold, Bachelor of Science in Biology, VPI Diploma, 1925-06-09 (Folder 1)
  - Thomas William Sibold, High School Diploma, 1926 (Folder 1)
- Series III: Papers, 1935-1980
  - Nannie Virginia Sibold diary, 1935-1939 (Box 12)
  - Letters and VPI reunion materials, 1970-1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Memories, Mattie Lamb Tucker", 1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - VPI folder, n.d. (Box 12)
- Series IV: Photograph Albums
  - Photograph Albums (Box 11, Folder 12)